[
  {
      "question": "sudo apt update",
      "answer": "command is used to refresh your system's package index. "
    },
    {
        "question": "systemctl status jenkins",
        "answer": "It shows whether the Jenkins service is currently active, inactive, or failed"
      },
      {
        "question": "sudo systemctl start docker",
        "answer": "starts the Docker service on your computer"
      },
      {
        "question": "service docker status",
        "answer": "checks if the Docker service is running on older systems."
      },
      {
        "question": "sudo journalctl -fu docker.service",
        "answer": "shows real-time logs for the Docker service"
      },
      {
        "question": "grep",
        "answer": "used to search for and display lines in text files that match a specified pattern"
      },
      {
        "question": "grep ERROR file.txt",
        "answer": "finds and displays lines with ERROR in the file file.txt"
      },
      {
        "question": "grep -i ERROR file.txt",
        "answer": "finds and shows lines with ERROR in file.txt, regardless of case."
      },
      {
        "question": "grep -ir dosto /home/ubuntu",
        "answer": "searches for dosto in all files under /home/ubuntu, ignoring case and including subdirectories."
      },
    
      {
        "question": "find /home/ubuntu -name \"*.txt\"",
        "answer": "searches for all .txt files in the /home/ubuntu directory and its subdirectories."
      },
    
      {
        "question": "awk",
        "answer": "awk is used to manipulate and analyze text."
      },
    
      {
        "question": "awk '/WARN/' app.log",
        "answer": "prints lines containing WARN from the app.log file."
      },
    
      {
        "question": "awk '/WARN/ {print $1, $2}' app.log",
        "answer": "prints the first and second columns of lines containing WARN from the app.log file"
      },
    
      {
        "question": "awk 'NR >= 1 && NR <= 10 && /WARN/ {print NR}' app.log",
        "answer": "prints the line numbers of lines containing WARN from the first 10 lines of app.log."
      },
      {
        "question": "awk '/WARN/ {print NR}' app.log",
        "answer": "prints the line numbers of lines containing WARN from the app.log file."
      },
      {
        "question": "awk '$1 >= \"2015-07-01\" && /WARN/ {print NR}' app.log",
        "answer": " prints the line numbers of lines where the first column is on or after \"2015-07-01\" and contains \"WARN\""
      },
      {
        "question": "qa_analysis.log",
        "answer": "is a log file for quality assurance analysis data."
      },
      {
        "question": "cat qa_analysis.log",
        "answer": "displays the contents of the qa_analysis.log file."
      }
      
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
  ]